Saurabh S. Uchil

Melbourne, VIC -3000 | saurabh.uchil@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/saurabh-uchil07

PROFILE SUMMARY

Enthusiastic about implementing and launching new projects. Previously had the experience of working with business requirements and translating them into technical solutions along with timely delivery of the products. Familiar with the Agile working environment while working for university projects. Looking forward to starting the career as an entry-level software engineer or software developer with a reputed firm driven by technology which will help me grow my current skills and learn new expertise.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Java | C++ | HTML | React JS | Java Script | C | Python | Object Oriented Software Design | Cloud Services | SQL | PHP | Web Application Development | Swift |

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Trainee Engineer - Marine Electricals Pvt Ltd, Mumbai

5/02/2018 - 06/06/2018

I have completed 4 months of internship where my responsibilities where:

- Create web pages for the company.
- Understand and develop UI designs for their product.
- Create user description manuals for the company products.

Support Engineer – FortuneTech, Mumbai

09/08/2017 - 03/02/2018

I have completed 6 months of internship where my responsibilities where:

- Respond to customer inquiries and assist in troubleshooting and resolving challenges.
- Assist management in creating training materials pertaining to computer troubleshooting and usage.
- Organize and file documentation pertaining to warranties and instructional guides for computer hardware.

PROJECTS

FITCUS

It is a web application designed using React JS and the backend is Google Fire store.

It enables fitness coaches to push their workout plans to the app itself so that end users can access them. This app enables the coaches to create workouts and add rules, repetitions to it.

Eagle Shark Game using Java.

It is a multiplayer strategy game designed using Java and concepts of Object of Oriented Programming. The game is designed and structured using various design patterns like abstract factory, façade etc.

LET'S CHAT

It is a web chat application that allows multiple users to chat at the same time. The front end was designed using HTML while the backend was supported by various cloud services like amazon relational database, amazon elastic beanstalk, google maps, google places.

HAND GESTURE RECOGNITION AND VOICE CONVERSION SYSTEM

In the final year of my bachelor's degree, we had made this project that consists of a glove that would recognize and then convert the actions into voice output.

Paper published: https://ijetae.com/files/Volume7Issue2/IJETAE_0217_16.pdf

EDUCATION

Master of Information Technology

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology July 2018 – July 2020

Bachelor of Engineering – Computer Engineering

Mumbai University
July 2013 – Aug 2017

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

RMIT UNIVERSITY STUDENT UNION(RUSU)

July 2018 - Mar 2020

Here my responsibilities were:

- Arrange student meetings.
- Plan and arrange student fun parties.
- Participate in the student job fairs.

HELPAGE INDIA

Here I was responsible for arranging health camps for the under privileged people and participated in many donation drives.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Playing football at a professional level has always been a passion for me.
- Managing social and technical events has always been a key interest of choice.
- This eventually helps me to enhance my personal skills and to stay in contact with people and the trending technological advancements.
- All physical and tactical sports & events.

LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

- English: fluent (speaking, reading, writing)
- Hindi: native language